-你好啊 莉莉 -你好啊
- Aloha, Lily. - Aloha.
不行 得再来一次
Oh, wait. Let's do it one more time.
-小狗狗挡住小脸蛋了 -的确
- The doggy was blocking her face. - Yeah,
-回去再来 -我不要 我不要
- Go back. - No. No! No.
我可不要再来第三次
We're not doing it a third time.
瞧瞧谁来了 茂伊岛上最美的人儿 夫人
There she is- the prettiest white woman on Maui. Milady.
说实话 当年克莱尔和我本来
Actually, Claire and I were supposed to
-是要来夏威夷来度蜜月的 -没错
- go to Hawaii for our honeymoon. - Mm-hmm.
可出现了点状况
But something else came up.
-我怀上了海莉 -都是哥的错
- I got pregnant with Haley. - My bad!
我们甚至连像样的婚礼都没办
We didn't even have a proper wedding.
就随便挑了一个礼拜二去法院登记了
We just went down to the courthouse on a Tuesday.
我从此就被判"无期婚姻"徒刑 且不准假释
The judge sentenced me to life with no chance of parole.
当时可是你求我嫁给你的
You begged me to marry you.
没错 我求了
It's true. I did.
慢点 我的娘子 来吧
Oh! Hold on, my bride. Allow me!
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
浪漫一下 天呐 你真重
Being romantic. God, you're solid.
亲爱的 快放我下来 慢慢来 好了
Sweetie, put me down. Go on. Okay.
亲爱的 别这样
Honey, come on.
让我们把这次假期当成在度蜜月吧
Let's turn this vacation into a honeymoon.
亲爱的 我可是带着孩子来旅行的
Sweet pea, I'm a mom traveling with my kids.
对我来说 这不是度假
For me, this is not a vacation.
是出差 跟我走
It's a business trip. Let's go.
真不错
This'll do.
-太漂亮了 -大家好啊
- It's beautiful. - Aloha!
欢迎入住四季酒店茂伊店
Hi! Welcome to the Four Seasons Maui.
感觉怎样 曼尼
What do you think, Manny?
宾至如归啊
I'm home.
我们居然还有自己的房间
I can't believe we have our own hotel room.
太棒了 这里还有个熨斗
Score! There's an iron in here!
你就不能把房间弄得整洁点吗
Don't you want to keep our room neat?
万一有客人来怎么办
You know, in case we entertain.
谁会来啊
Who would we entertain?
我看到儿童俱乐部里有好多可爱的小姑娘
I noticed some lovely tweens down by the kids' club.
没准我们能在泳池边找个机会搭讪
Maybe we can find a nice spot near them by the pool...
再奉上一杯"处女红"鸡尾酒
and send over a couple of virgin mai tais.
她们没准喜欢我们这种成熟老练的男人
They may be interested in two sophisticated men like us.
我是浴室战神
I am a bathroom martian!
我来自伟大的卫生间星云
I am from the nebula of the Great Toilet.
给我来一个你们这里最大的芝士汉堡
I want the biggest cheeseburger you got.
把沙拉换成薯条
Instead of salad, I want fries.
把水果换成辣薯条
Instead of fruit, I want chili fries.
海莉 亲爱的 别玩手机了
Haley, sweetie, put the phone down
快涂点防晒霜
and put on some sunscreen. Please?
我们得时刻盯着这些孩子
We have got to stay on these kids all day,
-不然他们准得晒伤 -绝对的
- or else they're gonna burn. - Totally.
他们就早上涂了那么一小点防晒霜
They put on the littlest bit of sunscreen in the morning,
就以为没事了
they think it's got them covered for the-
你是不是在透过我的墨镜偷看歌洛莉亚
Are you watching Gloria in my sunglasses?
是她在做慢动作 还是我在胡思乱想
Is she moving in slow motion, or is my brain doing that?
-菲尔 认真点 -继续说 我听着呢
- Phil, this is important. - Go ahead. I'm glistening.
嘿 大家好啊
Hey, everybody.
我们正要去看世界上最大的榕树
We're on our way to see the world's largest banyan tree.
有人想一起来吗
Does anybody want to come?
谁会吃饱了撑着 要离开这片仙境
Now, why in the hell would anyone want to leave paradise,
去坐闷热无比的车只为看一棵树
take a hot bus ride to see a tree?
我最欣赏卡梅隆的一点是
The great thing about Cameron is that,
他勇于探索 和我一样
uh, he's adventurous, like I am.
我们都喜欢入乡随俗
We-We both like to immerse ourselves in the culture
更多地了解本地居民
and really get to know the locals.
我们的朋友遍布全球
We've made friends all over the world.
我们至今还和伊伦加保持着联系
We're still in touch with Elunga,
他是我们在坦桑尼亚狩猎旅行时认识的
a man we met on safari in Tanzania.
我们经常寄旧衣服给他
We actually send him... all of our old clothes.
我们结识时 他还是个很善良的人
He was a very nice man when we met him,
但就最近的回信来看
but based on his recent letters,
我有点担心他已经变成军阀了
I have a small fear he's become a warlord.
嘿 我要去健身房运动下
Hey. I'm gonna go to the gym to work out a little bit.
你要一起来吗
You want to come with me?
我刚刚特地叫了一根超长吸管
I just ordered an extra-long straw
就是为了不想坐起来
to avoid accidentally doing a sit-up.
猜猜谁来电
Ah, look at this.
我弟弟
My brother.
干吗 蠢货
What's up, jackass?
生日快乐 你个二逼
Happy birthday, you dumb son of a bitch.
明天才是我的生日 蠢蛋
Birthday's tomorrow, moron!
真搞不懂你们兄弟俩
I never understood this relationship.
-63岁了对吧 -没想到你还会数数
- So, 63, right? - Hey, you can count!
你记得老爸就是63岁死的吧
You know Dad was 63 when he died. Huh?
-喂 - 多谢提醒
- Hello? - Thanks for reminding me.
别担心 是他不懂得好好保养身体
Ah, don't worry. He never took care of himself.
总是吃垃圾食品 喝得烂醉如泥
Ate like crap and drank too much.
管他呢 艾琳在求我...
Anyway, Irene's begging me for-
等等我 歌洛莉亚 我来了
Hey, Gloria, wait up. I'm coming.
我在想要不要给我们预定一个夫妻按摩
So, I was thinking we book a couples' massage.
我正巧看到一对在做
I accidentally looked in on one.
他们没看到我之前可放松呢
They seemed really relaxed until they noticed me.
海莉 够了 快挂电话
Haley, that's enough. Get off the phone.
卢克 裤子拉拉好
Luke, pull up your trunks!
你穿这身泳衣真好看
This bathing suit looks great on you.
谢谢夸奖 海莉 别打了 快
Thanks, sweetie. Haley, come on. Off the phone.
不是吧 凯拉把她的头发拉直了
No way. Keira got her hair straightened?
克莱尔 为表达对你的爱 我决定这么做
Claire, consider this a grand gesture of my love.
你干嘛...
What are you-
噢 天呐
Oh, my God!
-你都做了什么 -菲尔 你在想什么
- What did you do? - Phil, what are you thinking?
那手机可贵呢
That is an expensive cell phone.
好戏才刚刚开始
It's just the beginning.
做好准备吧 我要向你展开攻势了
Buckle your seat belt, lady. You're being wooed.
在自然界中 雄性通常会吃掉幼崽
In nature, fathers are known to eat their young.
是因为幼崽好吃吗 不是
Is it because they're delicious? No.
是因为它们想给雌性伴侣
It's because they want to give their female-
比如熊啊 长颈鹿啊 随便什么
bear, giraffe, what have you-
一个甜蜜的蜜月
the honeymoon they never had.
事先声明 我不是说吃孩子是可以原谅的
Just to be clear, I'm not condoning eating your kids,
可我知道长颈鹿这么做的本意是什么
but I sure as heck know why giraffes do it.
什么
What?
-起床来 懒虫 -别闹了 杰
- Come on, sleepy! - Ay, Jay!
快起床 宝贝 别赖床了
Come on, honey! Get out of bed!
我刚预订了个划艇
I just booked us on an outrigger.
可今天是你的生日
But it is your birthday.
你就不想睡个懒觉
You don't want to sleep in?
-快来 -不 不
- Come here. - No, no,
我刚从健身房回来 猜我刚举起多重
I just came from the gym. Guess how much I benched.
-不知道 500磅 -500磅
- I don't know. 500 pounds? - 500 pounds?
你当我是叉车啊
What am I, a forklift?
实话和你说吧
To tell you the truth,
我老弟那通电话把我吓惨了
that call from my brother scared the hell out of me.
我决定尽快练回健康身材
I decided to get in better shape quick.
我可不想步我老爸的后尘
Didn't want to end up like my old man.
不过他算是死于他热爱的事业中
Although he did die doing what he loved-
拒绝向来店里的嬉皮士提供服务
refusing service to hippies who came into his store.
曼尼是有史以来最差的室友
Manny is the worst roommate ever.
他看到什么都要叠起来
Everything he finds, he folds.
亲爱的 忍忍几天就过去了
Sweetie, it's only for a few more days.
昨晚还做了火灾演习
Last night we had a fire drill.
不是整个酒店 就我俩
Not the hotel. Just us.
-你们好啊 -你们好
- Hi, guys. - Hey.
今天准备去哪探险呢
So, what's today's big adventure?
我敢打赌孩子们肯定都想和你们去
I'll bet the kids want to go with you.
今天可是去个好地方 薰衣草牧场
Well, it is a big one- the lavender ranch,
-那里种45种不同的薰衣草哦 -45种哦
- where they grow 45 different varieties of lavender. - Forty-five.
听到没 孩子们 45种不同的薰衣草哦
Hear that, kids? Forty-five different varieties.
好吧 实在说不动他们 祝旅途愉快
Yeah, I can't sell that. Go with God.
那就没人和我们抢了
Oh. Well, more lavender for us.
米奇尔和我初遇时
When Mitchell and I first met,
我可能夸大了我对探险的狂热之情
I may have exaggerated my interest in adventurous travel...
我说我有很多此类经历
by implying that I had any.
可他偏偏最爱我这点
But it's one of the things he loves most about me,
导致我现在不能道出事实
and I can't tell him the truth now.
就好像路易斯告诉克拉克
It would be like Lewis telling Clark
他其实不喜欢徒步一样
that he didn't like to walk.
补充说明一下
Side note.
路易斯和克拉克夫夫是我们的一对好朋友
We're very good friends with a couple named Lewis and Clark.
克拉克在新奥尔良买了一块巨大的地皮
Clark bought a big, sparkly belt in New Orleans
他将之与政府当年购买路易斯安那州相提并论
that he calls his Louisiana Purchase.
妈妈 海莉一直偷我的ipod
Mom, Haley keeps stealing my iPod.
我的歌都在手机上 你让我怎么办
All my music is on my phone. What else am I supposed to do?
曼尼整天看新闻
Manny watches the news.
连你们都不怎么看新闻
You guys don't even watch the news.
你们好 对不起
Aloha. Hi. Sorry, folks.
这泳池是成人专用
This pool is for adults only.
-别回头 -什么
- Don't turn around. - What?
听我的 往前走就是了
Trust me. Just keep walking.
等等 你们要去哪儿
Wait! Where are you guys going?
爹妈
Guys?
什么情况
What just happened?
我们到时能一边喝薰衣草茶
Ooh, so we can drink lavender tea
一边吃薰衣草饼
while eating lavender scones.
真棒 一整天都这么过还是怎么着
Oh, neat! So, is this an all-day thing or-
不是的 我知道你在想什么 小卡
Oh, no. I know what you're thinking, Cam.
别担心 我们还有时间参观捕鲸村落
Don't worry. We'll still have time for the whaling village.
那就好
Oh. Good. So-
很好
Okay.
-我不行 -什么
- I can't. - What?
我不想去了
I don't want to go.
我知道我说过
I know I said
我不是那种慵懒不爱动的人
I'm not a stay-by-the-pool type of guy,
可我骨子里就是 米奇尔
but I really am, Mitchell.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
我是喜欢探险
I'm saying that I like adventure,
可也用不着每分每秒都投身于此
but not every minute of every day.
你能自己一个人去吗
Can you just go by yourself?
那可是薰衣草农场啊
But... the lavender ranch-
注定要两个相爱的人一起享受的
It's- It's something two men are meant to do together.
-到底去不去 -我去
- On or off, folks? - Well, I'm on.
我不去
I'm off.
想想你错过了什么 小卡
Think about what you're missing, Cam.
整个牧场都是薰衣草哦
It's an entire ranch full of lavender.
你说得再天花乱坠都没用
You're not making the compelling case you think you are!
嘿 小兔崽子们
Hey, you little monkey!
别光站着 给我下去
No standing around! There you go!
又一个下来咯 下去
Here goes another one! There you go!
Here comes another one! There you go!
我以为你是我们家的小孩
I thought you were one of ours!
杰 当心点
Hey, Jay! Be careful!
别伤着人家 特别是你自己
You're gonna hurt somebody- like you!
别太惬意哦
Don't get too comfortable.
-我刚定好了网球场 -好
- I reserved us a tennis court. - Yay.
我以为嫁给一个老头的好处之一是
I thought that one of the advantages of marrying an older guy...
生活能过的轻松点
was that I was going to be able to relax.
可他又是游泳又是跑步又是划船
But all this swimming and running and rowing-
简直跟我的同胞们偷渡来美国的过程差不多
It's just like how some of my relatives got into this country.
你知道吗
You know- Mmm.
你比我们结婚时更漂亮了
You look prettier now than the day we got married.
亲爱的 你也更帅了
Oh, honey. And you are even more handsome.
我有在浴室里偷偷练俯卧撑
I did push-ups in the bathroom.
你真"幽默"
You're funny.
-你真好 -我一直都这么好
- You're nice. -I have always been nice.
我也一直很幽默
I've always been funny.
好吧
Well-
老妈 老爸
Mom! Dad!
别理她 可能是在叫其他人
Ignore her. That could be anyone.
菲尔和克莱尔·邓菲
Phil and Claire Dunphy?
海莉 亲爱的 怎么了
Yes, Haley, honey? What is it?
我去和隔壁的一些孩子
I'm gonna go get some shaved ice at the hotel
一起去吃点刨冰
next door with some kids.
-什么孩子 -就是在泳池边的那些
- What kids? - Just some kids I met at the pool.
-好吧 我得去看看 -克莱尔 别去
- Okay. Um- I should go with her and - Claire, no.
你得学会放手
You have to learn to let go.
把家庭度假变成度蜜月 要坚持做到哦
Turning a family vacation into a honeymoon takes commitment.
你能做到 猛虎之眼
You can do it. Eye of the tiger.
怎么说
Hello!
-至少得见见他们 -不行
- I should at least meet them. I - No.
你这可不是猛虎之眼
That is not eye of the tiger.
好吧 海莉 亲爱的 玩的开心点
All right, Haley, honey, go and have fun,
但可不能上陌生人的车
but don't get in anybody's car...
准时回来参加你外公的生日 知道了吗
and be back in time for your grandfather's birthday dinner, okay?
谢谢
Thank you!
-好吧 快去快回 -再见 亲爱的
- Okay! All right! - Bye, honey!
天呐
Oh, God.
这感觉真是又诡异又舒爽
That feels weird and good all at once.
当然 刚刚我也靠在那喷头上呢
I know. I was leaning up against that nozzle a minute ago.
-嘿 -你回来啦 感觉怎样
- Hey. - Hey, you're back. How was it?
卡梅隆 那真是我这辈子
Ah! Cameron, it was the most incredible thing
见过最美的东西
I've ever seen in my entire life.
-真的吗 -你到我在那碰到谁了吗
- Really? - You know who else was there?
-谁 -艾尔顿·约翰
- Who - Elton John.
-不会吧 -真的 他也被美景深深吸引了
- No- -Yes, and he was so blown away by the beauty of it,
你坐在用薰衣草装点的钢琴前
he sat down... at their lavender piano
演奏了一曲《小舞人》
and played "Tiny Dancer."
我顿感心有灵犀 因为他也热爱探险
And we bonded, because he too likes adventure.
-这些都是真的吗 -不 当然是假的
- Did that really happen? - No, that didn't really happen.
我只是觉得
I'm just...
只是想报复你抛弃我
trying to get back at you for bailing on me.
很抱歉 如果你真想和我一起
I'm sorry. If it means anything,
我们在这什么也不做也很开心
we've been relaxing here doing nothing.
-也许明天你能和我们一起 -不行
- Maybe you can join us tomorrow. - No, I can't- I just don't-
-我实在不觉得放松有什么意思 -我懂
- I don't find relaxing that relaxing. - I understand.
你生性如此难再改
You are who you are.
-蕾拉妮 -来了
- Leilani. - Yes.
你知道吗 我想可能是我受我爸妈的影响
You know what? I think it's because of my parents.
当然了 奇普
It always is. Kipu!
我是说 和我爸妈一起度假
I mean, vacation with my mom and dad
就像坐在两个雕像旁边一样
was them sitting around like statues...
我和克莱尔唯一能找到的乐子就是
when, the only thing that me and Claire could do for excitement was-
坐着听自己的皮肤晒得吱吱作响
Was sit around and listen to my skin sizzle.
-你真可怜 苏 -来了
- You poor thing. Sue? - Yes.
那就是为什么 每当我出来度假
So, that's, like- That's why, when I'm on vacation,
我就想出去见见当地人
I want to go out and meet the locals.
想让自己融入当地的文化 明白吗
I want to immerse myself in the culture, you know?
我可不想一整天都这么懒洋洋的
I don't want to sloth around- Ah!
我的个嘎嘎 太舒服了
Sweet Lady Gaga, that is good.
谢谢
Thank you.
这叫什么
What's this called?
幸福
Happiness.
我很好奇 是我们浴室里的沙子没弄走
I'm curious. Is there any sand left on the beach,
还是你带回我们浴室里来了
or did you bring it all up to our bathroom?
抱歉了 老妈
Sorry, Mom.
而你现在又坐在我的亚麻夹克上
And now you're sitting on my linen jacket.
我就不能有件像样的东西吗
I guess I can't have nice things.
-对不起 我不知道它在那 -没关系
- Oh. I'm sorry. I didn't know it was there. - It's okay.
不 快停下
No! Stop!
我今晚可是要穿的
I'm wearing that tonight!
我把你的衣服弄皱咯
I'm wrinkling your linen! I'm wrinkling your linen!
这是你逼我的 滚出去
Ooh! You know what? Out!
给我滚出去 这样不行
I want you out! This isn't working!
我不管你去哪里 只要别在这就行了
I don't care where you go, as long as you don't stay here!
你说什么
What are you saying?
你听不懂"出去"两个字吗
What don't you understand about "Out"?
走就走 我去和我姐姐们住
Fine. I'll just move in with my sisters.
是谁小便都不能瞄准 到处都是
Oh, no! Who will pee all over the bathroom floor?
我当时还在刷牙呢 高难度
I was brushing my teeth at the same time.
你给我试试看
You try to do that.
你今天都做了什么
What'd you do today?
-我打了个盹 -真的吗
- I napped. - You did?
-我好几年都没打过盹了 -感觉很棒 对吧
- I haven't napped in years. - Yeah. It feels good, doesn't it?
嗯 又奇怪又舒爽
Mm-hmm. Good and weird.
就像无边泳池里的那个喷头一样
Kinda like that one nozzle in the infinity pool.
不知道 菲尔把那给占了
I wouldn't know. Phil was hogging it.
是我的错觉还是莉莉真的比以前更放松了
Is it me, or is Lily more relaxed here?
不是你的错觉
Oh, yes. She is.
我觉得她是受到我们的影响了
I think it's because she's really picking up on our energy, you know?
就好像要是我们紧张了 她也会跟着紧张
It's like, if we're tense, she's gonna be tense.
我觉得我们得把这种正能量带回家
And I think we need to bring this new energy home.
可以使我们更好地为人父母
It's gonna make us better parents-
-你关了 -什么 什么情况
- You blocked the - What? What happened?
-你没带她出来 -我以为你带着
- You didn't bring her out! - I thought you had her!
来吧 让我来为你画张像
Come on. Let me paint you.
亲爱的 会不会太重口味了
Oh, sweetie. That is so creepy.
人都到哪去了
Where is everyone?
好吧 我来说说大家的想法
Okay. Let me just say what everyone's thinking.
我的夹克太皱了
My jacket's a mess.
本不该这样的
It wouldn't be,
可有人竟然用熨斗来烤奶酪
but someone used the iron to make grilled cheese.
我有面包 有奶酪 外加一个熨斗
I had bread, I had cheese and I had an iron.
我还能怎么做
What was I supposed to do?
孩子们 别胡闹 我们不在乎
Kids, kids. We don't care.
大家好啊
Hola, hola!
抱歉我迟到了 杰去哪了
Hey. So sorry I'm late. Where is Jay?
他不是和你在一起吗
He's not with you?
没啊 他早就下来了
No, he came down long time ago.
别担心 我去找找
Oh, don't worry. I'll go have a look around.
是啊 他也许正在海里
Yeah, he's probably in the ocean trying to
用牙齿拖船呢
pull a tugboat with his teeth.
看看谁来了
Well, look who decided to join us.
-你姐呢 -她在浴室狂吐呢
- And where is your sister? - She is in our bathroom throwing up.
什么情况
Well, what happened? -
我看到她现在的样子也很痛心
You're not going to like this as much as I do,
可她喝多了
but she's drunk.
我就知道不该纵容她的
I-I knew I never should have let her-
有戏看咯
That's awesome.
我敢保证我们的浴室肯定更恶心
Guarantee our bathroom is still messier.
我的天呐 莉莉 电梯到哪去了
Oh, my God! Lily! Where is the elevator?
我不管了 我走楼梯去了
Where- I don't know! I'm taking the stairs!
莉莉 我们来救你了
Lily, we're coming for you!
嘿 你这是要去哪
Hey, you. Where you headed?
还记得先前在泳池 你说服我
Well, remember earlier in the pool when you convinced me...
放手让海莉去和隔壁的陌生人去玩
to let Haley go next door with complete strangers?
-你当时完全同意的 -没错
- And you were totally on board. - Yeah. Mm-hmm. Yeah, well,
可她现在喝醉了 还在上面狂吐
she got drunk, and now she's upstairs throwing up.
可她还是个孩子 谁给她的酒
But she's just a kid. Who would serve her?
是我们 亲爱的 我们亲手奉上的
We did, honey. On a silver platter.
你说服我要放轻松 随她去玩
You convinced me to relax and let go,
看看落下什么结果
and now this happens.
我很抱歉 别太为我们
I'm sorry, but we shouldn't feel bad...
因共享二人世界而付出的代价自责
About wanting a little time for ourselves.
亲爱的 这不是在度蜜月
Sweetie, this isn't a honeymoon.
我们已经为人父母 你得放弃那个想法了
We have kids. You have got to let this go.
从现在起 我不会让他们离开我的视线一步
From now on, I am not losing sight of them for two seconds.
什么都别想逃过我的法眼
Nothing gets past me.
找到杰了吗
Did you find Jay?
我有点担心了
I'm getting worried.
很抱歉 我得去处理一下海莉的问题
I'm sorry. I have to deal with Haley.
不用了 亲爱的 我去处理海莉
No. You know what, sweetie? I will deal with Haley.
你继续去找找老爸
You go see if you can find Dad.
我去外面找找
I'll look for him out there.
莉莉 你个小家伙是要去哪儿
Lily, where are you going, huh?
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
-对不起 -我的天呐
- I'm so sorry. - Oh, my God.
你在想些什么啊
Wow. What were you thinking?
有个孩子有身份证 她就买了些酒
One of the kids had an I.D., and she bought some drinks.
我喝了一口 结果就止不住了
I tried one, and then another one.
我真傻
It was stupid.
的确 的确很傻
Yes. Yes, it was stupid,
不过你还算幸运
but you are really lucky
没有遭遇更可怕的事
that this did not end as badly as it could have.
所以我们从小教育你
This is why we always say to you...
一旦喝醉 就会犯糊涂
when you drink, you make bad decisions.
我知道 我知道 只是
I know, I know. I just-
前一分钟还在返校节派对上喝酒
One minute you're having wine coolers at homecoming,
接下来
and the next...
我克莱尔就火遍全校了
the game of Truth or Claire sweeps your high school.
谢谢你没骂我
Thanks for not yelling at me.
亲爱的 那样就太狠心了
Oh, honey. That would just be cruel.
我会等到你酒醒了再骂你的
I'II wait till you feel better to yell.
我觉得我永远不会好起来了
I don't think I'll ever feel better.
每次喝酒都会这样吗
Does this happen every time you drink?
是的
Yes.
Yes, it does.
杰
Jay?
在这呢
Over here.
你在干什么呢
What are you doing?
我起不来了 一躺下我腰就折了
I'm stuck. I laid down, my back went out.
别担心 我会帮你的
Oh. Well, don't you worry. We're gonna get you out of here.
-抓着我 -好的 菲尔 这样做也许不大好
- Grab on. - Yeah, you know, Phil, this might not be the best-
不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no.
我要像飓风一样震撼到你[歌曲名]
I'm just gonna rock you- like a hurricane.
开个玩笑 你应该听不懂 来了
I'm kidding. You're too old to get that. Here we go.
等等 干嘛不去找工作人员
Wait. Why don't you just get someone who works here?
不 我可以的
No, this is gonna work.
准备好
And now- Oh, wow!
我抽筋了
There's spasming.
-别动 -我不想...
- Don't move. - No. I don't wanna get-
顺便说一下 我很感谢你给我们这次度假的机会
By the way, I just want to thank you for this trip.
这是我一生中最美好的一次度假
It's really been a vacation of a lifetime.
此地绝无基情
Nothing weird!
你们好
Aloha.
我把钱包放在前面口袋了 所以才...
I keep my wallet in my front pocket, so that's-
硬硬地顶着你
that's what that is.
我的脖子
Neck... going.
对不起
I'm sorry.
-有人在吗 帮帮忙 -快叫警卫
- Anyone! Anyone, help! - Alert security!
封锁这个岛
Seal off the island!
这边 这边
This- This way! This way!
莉莉
Lily!
是不是在找人啊
Aha. You looking for someone?
莉莉 我们担心死了 都怪我们说话说忘记了
Lily. We were so worried. We just got distracted.
-我们真是白痴 -别自责了
- Oh, we're idiots. - Ay! Don't beat yourself up.
我过去也老是把曼尼弄丢
I used to lose Manny all the time.
现在我把你爸也给丢了 这种事很平常
Now I lost your father. These things happen.
她说的对
She's right, you know.
她是不是说我爸失踪了
Did she say my father's missing?
我们总说会抽时间 可总被生活琐事缠绕
We say we'll make time, but life gets in the way.
我是说 我们的确已经为人父母
I mean, I know we're parents,
但难道不能同时做亲密爱人吗
but can't we be lovers too?
这也许是我最糟糕的一次生日了
This may be my worst birthday ever.
你终于来了
There you are!
亲爱的 你好
Oh, hi, honey.
他被卡在吊床上 当时实在太搞笑了
He was stuck in a hammock. It was actually really funny.
-我趴在他身"上"大概20分钟 -你好走了
- I was on top of him for, like, 20 minutes. - You need to go now.
晚安 亲爱的
Good night. Honey.
我的背疼发作了
My back seized up.
废话 都是因为
Yeah, because you overdid it
你接了那通电话后运动过量了
after that phone call about your father.
真不敢相信我已经和他当时一样老了
I can't believe I'm as old as he was.
等等 坐这缓缓
Wait. Sit down here.
-你会喜欢他的 我父亲 -没错
- You'd have liked him- my old man. - I'm sure.
他也会很喜欢你的
And he'd have loved you.
那老家伙可是魅力十足
My God, that guy- He was a charmer.
你不就是那种类型吗
Mmm, I know the type.
我们一起度过了很多欢乐时光
And we had a lot of fun.
可我要告诉你点事
But I'll tell you something.
我们的家庭度假可一点都不像这样
Our family vacations were nothing like this here.
每年在伊利湖畔租的农舍里
One week a year in a rented cottage on Lake Erie,
那里的蜘蛛都有这么大
spiders this big.
我倒蛮希望他能看到我们过上好日子了
I just wish he could have seen how things turned out.
要是你继续这样
Well, if you keep going like this,
你马上就能亲自告诉他了
maybe you can tell him yourself.
或者我也行 因为你也会把我害死的 杰
Or I can tell him, because you're about to kill me, Jay.
我得腿 胳膊和背 全身上下都在痛
My legs, my arms, my back- everything is sore.
我把你"折腾"得筋疲力尽是吧
So I wore you out, huh?
不不 别得意忘形 老家伙
Oh, no, no, no. Don't get cocky, old man.
我坐下去至少还能再站起来
When I sit down, I can still get up. Eh.
好了 过来吧
Hey, uh- Okay, come on.
过来 过来
Come here. Come here.
剩下的假期过的很愉快
The rest of the trip went better.
海莉的头不再晕了
Haley's room stopped spinning.
-是的 没错 -接着一个猴子
- Yes, it is. - And a monkey-
看看谁来了
There she is!
亲爱的 你好阿
Oh, honey! Hey!
-要来点松饼荷包蛋吗 太美味了 -不要
- Do you want some eggs Benedict? So creamy! - No.
不要吗
No?
杰如愿以偿地度过了他想要的轻松假期
Jay got back to the vacation he always wanted.
米奇和小卡也出去观光了
And Mitch and Cam managed to do some sightseeing...
在香蕉园里游览了一番
at a working banana plantation-
-莉莉 -在那貌似他们又丢了莉莉
- Lily! - Where they promptly lost Lily again.
你干嘛要把她打扮成和丛林一个颜色
Why did you dress her in jungle prints?
因为我觉得那样可爱
Because I thought it would be cute!
她会感觉她又回到了越南
She's gonna think she's back in Vietnam!
莉莉 莉莉 亲爱的
Lily! Lily, honey!
我和克莱尔 我们
Me and Claire, we-
我们度过了一段美好时光
we had a great time.
但我们仍没能度成蜜月
But we never did get that honeymoon.
我想我对这次的度假期望太高了
I think I just expected a little too much from this vacation.
有这份心意在就行了
You were so sweet to try.
现在想想真蠢
It was dumb.
像你说的那样 我们的激情消缺了
Like you said, the thrill is gone.
-我从来没这么说过 -不 的确没了
- I never said that. - No, it's over.
等等 我们可以再把时间稍微调回点
But wait. Put a few seconds back on the clock.
孩子们可是很积极的
The kid still has a few moves.
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
我搞明白为什么我们不能有个像样的蜜月了
I figured out why we couldn't have a honeymoon.
因为我们还没有举办过婚礼
Because we never had a wedding.
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
我还是猜不透你到底是喜欢还是讨厌
I still can't tell if you think this is lame or cool.
亲爱的 我当然喜欢
Honey, it's incredibly cool.
-看来我终于可以陪你走完红地毯了 -老爸
- Looks like I finally get to walk you down the aisle. - Daddy!
看来还得你带着我走
Ow! You better walk me.
好吧 我尽量
Okay. I'll do that.
我们今天欢聚一堂 共同来重温
We're here today to celebrate the renewing of the marriage vows...
菲尔和克莱尔喜结连理
of Phil and Claire.
今天 他们选择重申对彼此的爱意坚定不移
On this day they've chosen to reaffirm their love for each other.
你现在可以亲吻你的新娘了
You may kiss your bride. Oh!
我郑重宣布 他们依然是夫妇
I present to you, still as husband and wife,
邓菲夫妇
Mr. And Mrs. Dunphy.
欢迎你乘坐茂伊岛直飞洛杉矶的航班
Welcome to the nonstop flight from Maui to Los Angeles.
感谢你选择美国大陆航空
Thank for you choosing Continental Airlines.
谢谢你
Thank you.
亲爱的
You know, honey,
要是我有什么不测
if anything were ever to happen to me,
我希望你能再婚
I would want you to get remarried.
好的
Okay.
你答应得很快嘛
That was a little fast.
别乱想 我只是想让你开心
Oh, no. I just want to make you happy.
好吧
Okay.
-你有未来再婚的人选吗 -应该是薇姬·康洛伊
- Any idea of who you would remarry? - Vicky Conroy probably.
她和我一个办公室
She works in my office.
做事很有条例 孩子们都很喜欢她
She's very organized. The kids love her.
-你们在说薇姬吗 -是的
- Are you guys talking about Vicky? - Yeah.
妈妈 她棒极了
Mom, she's awesome.
我也想让你知道 要是我有什么不测
Just so you know, if something were to happen to me, I-
你不会发生不测的 别乱说
Something's gonna happen to you, all right.